# **MEGAN WILLIS**

https://megan.is meganclairewillis@gmail.com +44(0) 7432 55 9696 linkedin.com/in/megan-willis/

#### **SUMMARY**

UX consultant and researcher with a background in project management, and interests in front end development and accessibility.

Develops strong team and client relationships through open communication, consistent detail-oriented delivery, and practical knowledge of modern web design approaches, technologies and techniques within the wider context of the web.

For an overview of recent projects, please visit: https://megan.is

Tools include: Microsoft Office suite (including Project), Google Drive, Google Analytics/Tag Manager, InDesign, Photoshop, JIRA, Trello, Marvel App, and Sketch

#### **EXPERIENCE**

WhatUsersDo Jul 2016 - Present

**UX Researcher & Planner** A hybrid role encompassing both user research and project management, with a primary focus on researching website and app usability for a range of clients.

- Lead researcher on remote moderated and unmoderated usability research projects
- Responsible for planning, designing, carrying out, and analysing research, and reporting findings to clients
- Working closely with senior UX researchers to support with larger, more complex clients/ projects
- Managing both internal and freelance resource
- Clients include Eurostar, Direct Line, City of London Corporation, The Gleneagles Hotel, and Pottermore

## Digital Delivery Director & UX Consultant

table digital May 2016 - Present

Co-founder of table digital; a small web agency which focuses on working with good causes. Role covers business development, client management, project management, and UX consultancy.

- Creating proposals, pitching for, and subsequently delivering digital web work to scope, on time and on budget
- Running UX workshops (personas, user journeys, wireframing)
- Client onboarding and education, and sourcing and management of freelance resource
- Production of designer- and developer-ready UX documentation, and recommendations and guidance during design and build
- Client include Peckham Lido, Tabitha's Attic, and Westferry Printworks

# **MEGAN WILLIS**

https://megan.is meganclairewillis@gmail.com +44(0) 7432 55 9696 linkedin.com/in/megan-willis/

### Senior Digital Producer

We are Suburb Mar 2016 - Jul 2016 Lead PM on CMS integration projects, Magento e-commerce sites, apps, and immersive web experience projects.

- Successful, proactive management of multiple simultaneous end-to-end projects, delivered to deadline, budget, and scope
- Scheduling and communicating findings from user testing
- Writing proposals, scoping work and inputting to creative solutions
- Responsible for all team scheduling, finance and invoice management, and resourcing and leave management
- Clients include the Royal Academy of Arts, G . F Smith, and The Digital Consultancy

### **Digital Project Manager**

Radley Yeldar Jan 2015 - Mar 2016 Responsible for end-to-end delivery of web projects from flat story-led microsites to content managed corporate sites and apps with budgets up to £250,000.

- Working closely with strategists, UX consultants, designers and developers to establish and deliver against project KPIs/goals
- Co-creating and running workshops and requirements gathering sessions to promote inclusive, collaborative working with clients
- Resolution of difficult 'soft' challenges through client expectation management and addressing internal conflicts of opinion
- Management of internal teams, third-parties and freelancers
- Clients include Mace Group, Maersk, PwC, ARM, UKTI, and EMIS

## Junior Digital Project Manager

Radley Yeldar Sep 2013 – Dec 2014 Primarily maintained and grew SLA client relationships, while also managing multiple projects up to £100,000.

- Independently running client briefings and wash ups, and UX/Design workshops
- Managed projects, maintained content, and trained clients in sites built with Umbraco, Sitecore, and Wordpress
- Managing internal and third-party resource through use of multiple systems to deliver to agreed scope, timeline and budget
- Clients include GPE, intu, BAT, Drax, and Severn Trent

#### **EDUCATION**

Goldsmiths, University of London Psychology BSc (Hons), 2:1

#### REFERENCES

Additional information and references available upon request